Vincent Varghese

Covington, WA 98042

Phone: 516 384 4461 | Email: VinAVarghese@gmail.com

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/vincent-varghese

Portfolio: https://vav-portfolio.herokuapp.com/ | GitHub: https://github.com/VinAVarghese

Summary

A Full Stack Developer leveraging over five years of management experience to produce meaningful outputs while cultivating healthy team dynamics. Fluent in HTML, CSS, JavaScript and the full MERN stack with a full-stack development certificate from the University of Washington. Known among peers for strengthening teams and producing successful deliverables.

Technical Skills

JavaScript	Node.js	Git
JSON	Express	Responsive Design
AJAX	MongoDB	User Authentication
React.js	mySQL	Progressive Web Apps

Projects

PLANIT | GitHub https://tinyurl.com/yyr4x2jr | Link https://tinyurl.com/yxfigl36

- PLANIT is a collaborative, group trip planner.
- Led front-end development using React. Developed creative assets and directed UX/UI.
- Tools: Ant Design, React.js, React-animate-on-scroll, React-scroll, MongoDB

MixMe | GitHub https://tinyurl.com/yx9tevn6 | Link https://tinyurl.com/y598ysr2

- MixMe is a web application that searches drink recipes by ingredients.
- Led front-end development, created responsive layouts, creative assets and UX/UI.
- Tools: Foundation, CSSShake, JSON and AJAX

Spontaneously Now | GitHub https://tinyurl.com/yy2rqxny | Link https://tinyurl.com/y22c6alr

- Spontaneously Now is a web application that suggests random activities with a chosen category and allows for note taking for planning and journaling about activity
- Led back-end development, integrating four 3rd-party APIs with our mySQL database.
 Developed creative assets and directed UX/UI.
- Tools: Foundation, CSSAnimate, Sequelize, Express, Moment, Handlebars, AXIOS, AJAX

Experience

Consultant Mar 2020

The Church Co Remote

Providing customer satisfaction with excellent website setup via Wordpress

Acting District Manager

Aug 2019 – Dec 2019

CityMD Seattle, WA

- Successfully led 8 urgent care clinics during a company transition
- Maintained excellent Press Ganey scores and reviews from patients during transition

Site Manager

Jun 2018 - Dec 2019

CityMD

Seattle, WA

- Was directly responsible for clinic's customer service experience and produced the top
 Press Ganey scores in the region for customer satisfaction
- Entrusted with additional responsibility of tracking and submitting staff's DOH licensing

Assistant Site Manager

Sep 2017 – Jun 2018

CityMD

Seattle, WA

 Trusted by Regional Manager to solely preform Site Manager duties for six months to help the company during a staff transition

Information & Public Awareness Manager

Jan 2014 – Dec 2016

Vision Rescue

Mumbai, MH, India

- Increased social media engagement from no activity to a global presence
- Created and oversaw a reporting system to relay on-field impact data to partners
- Recruited and liaised local and international partnerships, effectively presenting to corporate boards and larger auditoriums

Education

Bootcamp Certificate: University of Washington, Seattle, WA

A 12-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js, and React

Bachelors Degree: Alphacrucis College, Sydney, NSW, Australia

A Bachelors in Contemporary Ministry, focusing on leadership. Upon graduating, received the "Outstanding Graduate Award: Exemplary Achievement & Leadership"